CaixaForum Madrid Garden: This is the vertical garden of CaixaForum Madrid, a contemporary art museum in a former power station. The vertical garden, a wall full of plants, is very photogenic.
Jardín del CaixaForum Madrid: Este es el jardín vertical del CaixaForum Madrid, un museo de arte contemporáneo en una antigua central eléctrica.  El jardín vertical, una pared llena de plantas, es muy fotogénico.
Fountain of the Galapagos:  Monumental fountain in Retiro Park, built in the 19th century to celebrate the birth of Infanta Isabel. Design with turtles, dolphins and other marine animals.
Fuente de los Galápagos:  Fuente monumental en el Parque del Retiro, construida en el siglo XIX para celebrar el nacimiento de la Infanta Isabel. Diseño con tortugas, delfines y otros animales marinos.
Calle de San Jerónimo (San Jeronimo Street): Historic street connecting Puerta del Sol with Paseo del Prado, near the Congress. Commercial, with shops, restaurants and emblematic buildings.
Calle de San Jerónimo: Calle histórica que conecta Puerta del Sol con Paseo del Prado, cerca del Congreso.  Comercial, con tiendas, restaurantes y edificios emblemáticos.
Calle de Alcalá (Alcalá Street): One of the longest and most important streets in Madrid. From Puerta del Sol to the east. Historic buildings, shops, theaters and places like Cibeles and Retiro.
Calle de Alcalá: Una de las calles más largas e importantes de Madrid. Desde la Puerta del Sol hacia el este. Edificios históricos, tiendas, teatros y lugares como Cibeles y Retiro.
Congress of Deputies: Building of the Cortes Generales, the Spanish Parliament. On Carrera de San Jerónimo, a neoclassical building representative of politics.
Congreso de los Diputados: Edificio de las Cortes Generales, el Parlamento español. En la Carrera de San Jerónimo, edificio neoclásico representativo de la política.
Retiro Park: Madrid's most famous park. Green oasis for walking, relaxing, boating, visiting the Crystal Palace or enjoying shows.
Parque del Retiro: El parque más famoso de Madrid. Oasis verde para pasear, relajarse, remar, visitar el Palacio de Cristal o disfrutar de espectáculos.
Statue of Charles III: Equestrian statue in honor of King Charles III, "the best mayor of Madrid", in the center of Puerta del Sol.
Estatua Carlos III: Estatua ecuestre en honor al rey Carlos III, "el mejor alcalde de Madrid", en el centro de la Puerta del Sol.
Calle de Donoso Cortés (Donoso Cortés Street): In the Chamberí neighborhood, a local residential and commercial area with shops, restaurants and markets, less touristy.
Calle de Donoso Cortés: En el barrio de Chamberí, zona residencial y comercial local con tiendas, restaurantes y mercados, menos turística.
Puerta del Sol (Sun Gate): Heart of Madrid, emblematic place of Spain. Bustling square, meeting point, Kilometer Zero and New Year's Eve clock.
Puerta del Sol: Corazón de Madrid, lugar emblemático de España. Plaza bulliciosa, punto de encuentro, Kilómetro Cero y reloj de campanadas de fin de año.
Plaza de Cibeles (Cibeles Square): Beautiful and representative square with the Cibeles Fountain. Surrounded by the Cibeles Palace, Bank of Spain and Buenavista Palace.
Plaza de Cibeles: Plaza bonita y representativa con la Fuente de Cibeles. Rodeada del Palacio de Cibeles, Banco de España y Palacio de Buenavista.
Gran Vía (Great Way/Grand Avenue): Madrid's most famous and vibrant avenue, the "Madrid Broadway". Theaters, shops, restaurants, cinemas and historic buildings.
Gran Vía: La avenida más famosa y vibrante de Madrid, el "Broadway madrileño". Teatros, tiendas, restaurantes, cines y edificios históricos.
Puerta del Sol (Sun Gate): Heart of Madrid, emblematic place of Spain. Bustling square, meeting point, Kilometer Zero and New Year's Eve clock.
Puerta del Sol: Corazón de Madrid, lugar emblemático de España. Plaza bulliciosa, punto de encuentro, Kilómetro Cero y reloj de campanadas de fin de año.
Plaza de España (Spain Square): Large square at the end of Gran Vía. Cervantes Monument, pond and buildings such as Torre de Madrid and Edificio España.
Plaza de España: Gran plaza al final de Gran Vía. Monumento a Cervantes, estanque y edificios como Torre de Madrid y Edificio España.
Calle de Preciados (Preciados Street): Very busy pedestrian shopping street. Ideal for shopping, department stores, fashion boutiques and bookstores.
Calle de Preciados: Calle comercial peatonal muy transitada. Ideal para compras, grandes almacenes, tiendas de moda y librerías.
Calle Mayor (Main Street): Historic street connecting Puerta del Sol with the Royal Palace. Old buildings, churches, traditional shops and restaurants.
Calle Mayor: Calle histórica que conecta Puerta del Sol con Palacio Real. Edificios antiguos, iglesias, tiendas tradicionales y restaurantes.
Fountain of Cibeles: Monumental fountain in Plaza de Cibeles. Goddess Cibeles in a chariot pulled by lions. Icon of Madrid and celebration place for Real Madrid.
Fuente de Cibeles: Fuente monumental en Plaza de Cibeles. Diosa Cibeles en carro tirado por leones. Icono de Madrid y lugar de celebración del Real Madrid.
Calle de Alcalá (Alcalá Street): One of the longest and most important streets in Madrid. From Puerta del Sol to the east. Historic buildings, shops, theaters and places like Cibeles and Retiro.
Calle de Alcalá: Una de las calles más largas e importantes de Madrid. Desde la Puerta del Sol hacia el este. Edificios históricos, tiendas, teatros y lugares como Cibeles y Retiro.
Plaza de España (Spain Square): Large square at the end of Gran Vía. Cervantes Monument, pond and buildings such as Torre de Madrid and Edificio España.
Plaza de España: Gran plaza al final de Gran Vía. Monumento a Cervantes, estanque y edificios como Torre de Madrid y Edificio España.
Puerta del Sol (Sun Gate): Heart of Madrid, emblematic place of Spain. Bustling square, meeting point, Kilometer Zero and New Year's Eve clock.
Puerta del Sol: Corazón de Madrid, lugar emblemático de España. Plaza bulliciosa, punto de encuentro, Kilómetro Cero y reloj de campanadas de fin de año.
Casa de Ruiz Velasco (Ruiz Velasco House): Historic building in Puerta del Sol. Striking facade and history linked to the Ruiz Velasco confectionery. Today it houses other businesses.
Casa de Ruiz Velasco: Edificio histórico en Puerta del Sol. Fachada llamativa e historia ligada a confitería Ruiz Velasco. Hoy alberga otros negocios.
Royal Post Office: Historic building in Puerta del Sol, headquarters of the Presidency of the Community of Madrid. Famous clock for New Year's Eve chimes.
Real Casa de Correos: Edificio histórico en Puerta del Sol, sede de Presidencia de Comunidad de Madrid. Reloj famoso para campanadas de fin de año.
Telefónica Building: Emblematic building on Gran Vía, a pioneering skyscraper in Madrid. Former headquarters of Telefónica, today a cultural and exhibition space.
Edificio Telefónica: Edificio emblemático de Gran Vía, rascacielos pionero en Madrid. Antigua sede de Telefónica, hoy espacio cultural y expositivo.
Calle de Alcalá (Alcalá Street): One of the longest and most important streets in Madrid. From Puerta del Sol to the east. Historic buildings, shops, theaters and places like Cibeles and Retiro.
Calle de Alcalá: Una de las calles más largas e importantes de Madrid. Desde la Puerta del Sol hacia el este. Edificios históricos, tiendas, teatros y lugares como Cibeles y Retiro.
Calle de Álvarez Gato (Álvarez Gato Street): Small street that leads into Puerta del Sol, known as a meeting point for artists and intellectuals. Sometimes called "Alley of the Cat".
Calle de Álvarez Gato: Pequeña calle que desemboca en Puerta del Sol, conocida como punto de encuentro de artistas e intelectuales. A veces "callejón del Gato".
Gran Vía (Great Way/Grand Avenue): Madrid's most famous and vibrant avenue, the "Madrid Broadway". Theaters, shops, restaurants, cinemas and historic buildings.
Gran Vía: La avenida más famosa y vibrante de Madrid, el "Broadway madrileño". Teatros, tiendas, restaurantes, cines y edificios históricos.
Gran Vía Metro Station: Gran Vía metro station, very busy and renovated with a modern and functional design.
Metro de Gran Vía: Estación de metro de Gran Vía, muy concurrida y renovada con diseño moderno y funcional.
Congress of Deputies: Building of the Cortes Generales, the Spanish Parliament. On Carrera de San Jerónimo, a neoclassical building representative of politics.
Congreso de los Diputados: Edificio de las Cortes Generales, el Parlamento español. En la Carrera de San Jerónimo, edificio neoclásico representativo de la política.
Gran Vía (Great Way/Grand Avenue): Madrid's most famous and vibrant avenue, the "Madrid Broadway". Theaters, shops, restaurants, cinemas and historic buildings.
Gran Vía: La avenida más famosa y vibrante de Madrid, el "Broadway madrileño". Teatros, tiendas, restaurantes, cines y edificios históricos.
Puerta del Sol (Sun Gate): Heart of Madrid, emblematic place of Spain. Bustling square, meeting point, Kilometer Zero and New Year's Eve clock.
Puerta del Sol: Corazón de Madrid, lugar emblemático de España. Plaza bulliciosa, punto de encuentro, Kilómetro Cero y reloj de campanadas de fin de año.
Atocha Station: Main train station in Madrid and transport hub. Houses an impressive indoor tropical garden.
Estación de Atocha: Principal estación de tren de Madrid y centro de transporte. Alberga un impresionante jardín tropical interior.
Gran Vía (Great Way/Grand Avenue): Madrid's most famous and vibrant avenue, the "Madrid Broadway". Theaters, shops, restaurants, cinemas and historic buildings.
Gran Vía: La avenida más famosa y vibrante de Madrid, el "Broadway madrileño". Teatros, tiendas, restaurantes, cines y edificios históricos.
Calle de Preciados (Preciados Street): Very busy pedestrian shopping street. Ideal for shopping, department stores, fashion boutiques and bookstores.
Calle de Preciados: Calle comercial peatonal muy transitada. Ideal para compras, grandes almacenes, tiendas de moda y librerías.
Puerta del Sol (Sun Gate): Heart of Madrid, emblematic place of Spain. Bustling square, meeting point, Kilometer Zero and New Year's Eve clock.
Puerta del Sol: Corazón de Madrid, lugar emblemático de España. Plaza bulliciosa, punto de encuentro, Kilómetro Cero y reloj de campanadas de fin de año.
Galería Canalejas (Canalejas Gallery): Luxurious shopping center in the center of Madrid, near Puerta del Sol. High-end shops and exclusive restaurants in an elegant setting.
Galería Canalejas: Lujoso centro comercial en el centro de Madrid, cerca de Puerta del Sol. Tiendas de alta gama y restaurantes exclusivos en entorno elegante.
Plaza de Canalejas (Canalejas Square): Small and elegant square next to Galería Canalejas, in the center of Madrid.
Plaza de Canalejas: Plaza pequeña y elegante junto a Galería Canalejas, en el centro de Madrid.
Puerta del Sol (Sun Gate): Heart of Madrid, emblematic place of Spain. Bustling square, meeting point, Kilometer Zero and New Year's Eve clock.
Puerta del Sol: Corazón de Madrid, lugar emblemático de España. Plaza bulliciosa, punto de encuentro, Kilómetro Cero y reloj de campanadas de fin de año.
Gran Vía (Great Way/Grand Avenue): Madrid's most famous and vibrant avenue, the "Madrid Broadway". Theaters, shops, restaurants, cinemas and historic buildings.
Gran Vía: La avenida más famosa y vibrante de Madrid, el "Broadway madrileño". Teatros, tiendas, restaurantes, cines y edificios históricos.
Four Seasons Hotel Madrid: Luxury hotel of the Four Seasons chain in a historic building near Puerta del Sol. One of the most exclusive hotels in Madrid.
Four Seasons Hotel Madrid: Hotel de lujo de la cadena Four Seasons en edificio histórico cerca de Puerta del Sol. Uno de los hoteles más exclusivos de Madrid.
Calle de Preciados (Preciados Street): Very busy pedestrian shopping street. Ideal for shopping, department stores, fashion boutiques and bookstores.
Calle de Preciados: Calle comercial peatonal muy transitada. Ideal para compras, grandes almacenes, tiendas de moda y librerías.
Plaza de Isabel II (Isabel II Square): Also known as Plaza de Ópera, in front of the Royal Theatre. Lively square with terraces and a popular meeting place.
Plaza de Isabel II: También conocida como Plaza de Ópera, frente al Teatro Real. Plaza animada con terrazas y lugar de encuentro popular.
Retiro Park: Madrid's most famous park. Green oasis for walking, relaxing, boating, visiting the Crystal Palace or enjoying shows.
Parque del Retiro: El parque más famoso de Madrid. Oasis verde para pasear, relajarse, remar, visitar el Palacio de Cristal o disfrutar de espectáculos.
Casino de Madrid (Casino of Madrid): Elegant modernist building near Puerta del Sol and Calle de Alcalá. Private social club with event rooms and a restaurant.
Casino de Madrid: Edificio elegante modernista cerca de Puerta del Sol y Calle de Alcalá. Club social privado con salones de eventos y restaurante.
Arco de Cuchilleros (Arch of the Knifemakers): One of the most picturesque and famous entrances to Plaza Mayor. It is an arch with stairs that connects Plaza Mayor with Calle de Cuchilleros.
Arco de Cuchilleros: Una de las entradas más pintorescas y famosas a la Plaza Mayor.  Es un arco con escaleras que conecta la Plaza Mayor con la Calle de Cuchilleros.
Plaza de Isabel II (Isabel II Square): Also known as Plaza de Ópera, in front of the Royal Theatre. Lively square with terraces and a popular meeting place.
Plaza de Isabel II: También conocida como Plaza de Ópera, frente al Teatro Real. Plaza animada con terrazas y lugar de encuentro popular.
Plaza de España (Spain Square): Large square at the end of Gran Vía. Cervantes Monument, pond and buildings such as Torre de Madrid and Edificio España.
Plaza de España: Gran plaza al final de Gran Vía. Monumento a Cervantes, estanque y edificios como Torre de Madrid y Edificio España.
Plaza de Pedro Zerolo (Pedro Zerolo Square): Square in the Chueca neighborhood, LGTBIQ+ meeting point. Lively pedestrian square with bars and restaurants.
Plaza de Pedro Zerolo: Plaza en el barrio de Chueca, punto de encuentro LGTBIQ+. Plaza peatonal animada con bares y restaurantes.
Gran Vía (Great Way/Grand Avenue): Madrid's most famous and vibrant avenue, the "Madrid Broadway". Theaters, shops, restaurants, cinemas and historic buildings.
Gran Vía: La avenida más famosa y vibrante de Madrid, el "Broadway madrileño". Teatros, tiendas, restaurantes, cines y edificios históricos.
Plaza de España (Spain Square): Large square at the end of Gran Vía. Cervantes Monument, pond and buildings such as Torre de Madrid and Edificio España.
Plaza de España: Gran plaza al final de Gran Vía. Monumento a Cervantes, estanque y edificios como Torre de Madrid y Edificio España.
Calle de Preciados (Preciados Street): Very busy pedestrian shopping street. Ideal for shopping, department stores, fashion boutiques and bookstores.
Calle de Preciados: Calle comercial peatonal muy transitada. Ideal para compras, grandes almacenes, tiendas de moda y librerías.
Calle de la Montera (Montera Street): Shopping street connecting Puerta del Sol with Gran Vía. Pedestrian with clothing and footwear stores, and a great atmosphere.
Calle de la Montera: Calle comercial que conecta Puerta del Sol con Gran Vía. Peatonal con tiendas de ropa y calzado, y mucho ambiente.
Calle del Duque de Alba (Duke of Alba Street): Street near Plaza Mayor and San Miguel Market. Traditional shops and charming restaurants.
Calle del Duque de Alba: Calle cerca de Plaza Mayor y Mercado de San Miguel. Tiendas tradicionales y restaurantes con encanto.
Gran Vía (Great Way/Grand Avenue): Madrid's most famous and vibrant avenue, the "Madrid Broadway". Theaters, shops, restaurants, cinemas and historic buildings.
Gran Vía: La avenida más famosa y vibrante de Madrid, el "Broadway madrileño". Teatros, tiendas, restaurantes, cines y edificios históricos.
Calle de Preciados (Preciados Street): Very busy pedestrian shopping street. Ideal for shopping, department stores, fashion boutiques and bookstores.
Calle de Preciados: Calle comercial peatonal muy transitada. Ideal para compras, grandes almacenes, tiendas de moda y librerías.